Hello, everyone.
Good afternoon, everyone.
I am Han Wei, the general manager of Cologne China.
I am also the host of this event.
After three years of epidemic, we can finally restart the online and online dual-channel user exchange conference.
On behalf of our team, I would like to thank everyone for taking the time to come to our site.
At the same time, I would like to thank our online partners for their active participation.
As usual, at the user exchange conference, we will invite many guests from various companies
to share their project experience and use experience.
I believe that their wonderful sharing will bring you a very different experience
and give you a very meaningful behind-the-scenes experience.
Our activity today will officially start.
First of all, I would like to invite our Chinese team teacher, Sherry,
to bring you the new features of Marvelous Design 12.
Let's give a round of applause to Sherry.
Good afternoon, everyone.
I believe that some of you may have seen me for the first time.
I am Sherry, who is always hiding behind the screen.
Today, I will share with you the new features of Marvelous Design 12.
How many of you have used Marvelous Design 12 before?
It seems that our new features introduction is very necessary.
In Marvelous Design 12, the first new feature that we have introduced is the auto-design of the clothes.
In the previous version of Marvelous Design, we have introduced the auto-design of the clothes and the auto-adjustment of the pieces.
These features need to be built on our clothes or on the virtual models to have the information of the clothes.
So in the previous version, we need to manually create the clothes for our new virtual models.
In the new version, first of all, in the past, we could not directly see the information of the clothes.
Now, in the 3D window, we can directly display the clothes of the clothes.
When we start displaying the clothes of the clothes, there will be a red grid next to it.
These grids are the information of the clothes that the clothes have.
Usually, the transformation or wearing of the clothes is based on the information of the clothes.
Now, when we import the virtual model of the OBJ model, we can select the auto-design of the clothes.
After our short calculation and simulation, the virtual model will bring the information of the clothes itself.
We can click on the display of the virtual model of the clothes.
We can see that there is a black grid around it, which is the information of the clothes it has.
Now, after we directly click on the auto-adjustment of the pieces, the clothes will automatically change according to the information of the clothes.
We do not need to manually create the clothes anymore.
In addition to the fact that the OBJ model can automatically create the clothes,
the FBX model can also automatically create the clothes.
However, one thing we need to pay attention to is that the information of the clothes
needs to ensure that the virtual model has a head when it is automatically created.
If the virtual model you import does not have a head,
then there is no way for it to automatically create the clothes.
The second new feature is the model line tool group.
When we choose to create and edit the model line tool,
our clothes will change from the original material or color to a white draft model.
At this time, we can directly edit clothes in 3D space,
instead of editing clothes in 2D window like before.
When we use the edit model line tool to drag the point,
you can see that the 2D and 3D window are modified simultaneously.
And when we modify a point,
other points and lines that are linked to it will be modified at the same time.
If we drag the line in 3D space,
you can see that the line will change infinitely.
So now we can not only edit clothes in 2D window,
but we can also edit clothes in 3D window.
Next, there is another feature called the model line tool group.
When we create a dress,
it is very convenient to use the model line tool to change the width of the dress.
For example, now I can change the width of the dress,
or if I want to shrink the dress,
I can shrink the dress.
This is the model line tool group.
In addition to using the model line tool group to change the dress,
we can also use the model line tool to modify the sleeves.
For example, now I can shrink the sleeves.
So now it is very convenient for us to modify these model lines in 3D window.
The next one is the mobile model line.
The mobile model line is a very common function
when we modify the side seam line of the dress,
or to adjust the length of the dress.
For example, sometimes we will feel that the side seam line,
if we move it forward or backward,
we can drag the side seam line directly into the 3D window,
which is the mobile model line.
It will also be modified in conjunction.
For example, if we move it backwards,
the front will become wider and the back will become narrower.
If we want to modify the length of the dress,
we will also use the mobile model line function.
If we drag the model line downwards,
the whole bottom line will be modified along the original side seam line.
It is not moved directly.
There is also the custom model line.
In fact, the custom model line,
because our model line is actually the outline of the panel,
so when we use the custom model line to cut,
we will see that the panel will automatically be cut.
If we click on the panel,
OK,
there will be a curve on the panel.
And after we finish drawing,
the panel will automatically be cut down,
and there will be a line.
So this function,
we will usually use it to make the cut and shape of the dress.
All of the operations of our creative styling line are symmetrical.
So as long as we draw one side,
the other side will automatically be symmetrical.
This function is actually for everyone to use in 3D window editing.
The next new function is to create a spiral version.
Now we can see the left and right sides of the dress created.
Its harmony effect is different.
When we make a lot of dresses,
we will need to use the ones on the right,
which are more viscous and have a richer fold.
And on the left side,
because we originally used a rectangular version,
its length difference is not enough.
So its fold is not large enough.
For a rectangular version,
it has a feature,
that is,
its length difference is relatively large.
For example,
its inner circle may be 120 cm,
and the outer circle is 180 cm.
In the middle,
there will be a 60 cm difference.
This difference will be reflected on the edge.
Because of this difference,
the fold of the edge here will become more.
So sometimes,
when we sew the edge of the contract,
we use a rectangular version.
Sometimes,
it looks like it has a lot of fold,
but it is not.
If the fold is not very obvious,
we can use this
rectangular version
to complete the effect we want.
Now,
when choosing to create a rectangular version,
we will have to fill in some numbers.
The first number is the radius.
If you don't know what this radius is,
actually,
when we modify this number,
there will be a light blue reference line.
This reference line tells us,
for example,
the first radius,
it is the radius from the center of our rectangle
to the starting position of our rectangle.
The smaller this number is,
the more the starting position of our rectangle is.
The next one is the length.
The length is the length of the side of our rectangle.
The inner side and the outer side are relative,
so if we change one of the numbers,
the other number will be modified in conjunction.
Usually,
our inner value
will match the length of
the horizontal row of our rectangle
or the horizontal row of our rectangle.
Now,
let's check the width of the side.
This side is the width of the rectangle.
The inner side is the length of the yellow line
on the inner side.
The outer side is the length of the yellow line
on the outer side.
This is the kind of shape
All you have to do is to understand the width of the edge of the river.
Our width can be set to a different value.
Next is the diameter.
Dismantle is the diameter of each circle of our spiral board.
It should be noted that the diameter of the diameter cannot be smaller than the width of the side edge.
Otherwise, our board will cross.
If the board is crossed, the board will not be able to be created.
Finally, the direction.
The direction can be set to a clockwise or a counterclockwise direction.
This is based on the position of our seal.
That's all about creating a spiral board.
The next function is the resetting of the cycle.
In the previous version, for example, in Marvelous Designer 11,
we added a smart loop tool.
In Marvelous Designer 12,
our smart loop can finally be created along the inner line.
The problem of not being able to create along the curved line before
has also been solved in the new version.
After creating the smart loop line, click Create.
It will automatically create a loop grid.
And now we can create a loop grid along the inner line
of the support loop points on the floating line updated in the previous version.
And if we manually create a loop structure,
we can also duplicate it along the inner line now.
In the past, if we wanted to separate the loop surface,
we needed to press Ctrl and Shift to do so.
In the new version, we can directly separate the loop surface.
Just click Create Loop Line and you can separate it manually.
In the process of separation, if there are five sides or more,
that is, there is no way to form a triangle or a quadrilateral structure,
this surface will show as orange.
This is to remind you that this is an unusable surface.
We need to continue to separate it again.
In the new version, we can now make a frame selection and choose the support point.
Then move or adjust these support points together.
If you press the Shift key and then click the frame selection,
you can select more.
Press the Ctrl key and the frame selection, you can select less.
The new feature is the close combination of the supporting points.
This is the connection in the middle.
Next.
Okay.
Here, when I was creating the top, I left some spaces in the middle on purpose.
I didn't do it on purpose.
And here, we choose to make all of them grid.
In the previous version, the structure of our top did not automatically inherit the powder line.
When we export it, we can't merge it.
In the new version, we have a close merge point.
In fact, it is used for the structure after the repackage.
In the new version, we have the function to lock the repackage.
If it is locked, we can only select the original version when we select the version at the 2D window.
If we choose to lock all the version outlines, the outline of the version will be displayed as gray, which means that it cannot be selected.
At this time, we can select the repackage alone.
After that,
we can select the next version.
Now let's separate these two versions and put them together.
Note that we have a pre-preserved point that is not close to the top.
In the previous version, when we export the OBJ file, we will choose the merge point.
The principle of the merge point is that it is based on the powder line to merge.
Therefore, since the structure we export is not based on the powder line,
the top of the top cannot be merged.
In the new version, as long as we choose to merge close to the top,
the top points on the side of the top surface can also be merged.
There is a value here.
This value is as long as the distance between the two points is less than this value.
After we click on the display, you can see that
the top points that have been merged will be shown as red.
In other words, even if your version has a top structure,
the top points will also be merged.
The top points that have not been merged will be shown as blue.
In the previous version, we have a pre-preserved point with some distance.
Now let's reduce the merge distance to 1.
When the distance between the two points is greater than 1,
the merge point will not be merged.
If we need to merge them,
we need to increase the number of merge points.
Then click on Confirm,
and we can export the top structure.
Let's import the OVJ file that we just merged.
Let's take a look at it.
In the previous version, it was merged.
This feature is also for everyone,
to make it convenient for everyone to use it in MMS Designer,
to block merge points after making a merge.
The next one is the fast key window.
This feature is for some of our software
who are not familiar with MMS Designer
and are not familiar with these fast keys.
Click on the title name,
and we can switch to the fast key window.
At this time, when we go to change the tool we are using,
the fast key window next to it
will pop up some of the common fast keys
when using this feature.
For example, if we choose to adjust the version,
the following are the common fast keys,
delete, copy, paste, etc.
They are all written on the side.
Then if we switch to the rabbit tool,
the window next to it will automatically
switch to some of the fast keys of the rabbit tool.
The orange one is the name of the fast keys we are using.
For example, the tools like the rabbit tool
or the editor tool.
Then on the left,
we not only have this fast key window in the second window,
but when we switch to the third window,
the fast key that is next to it
will also automatically switch to the corresponding tool.
If we click on these keys next to it,
we can fold the window.
We can fold the window
without using the fast keys.
This feature is actually very convenient
for everyone to use the fast keys
of the rabbit tool
to move the window out of the way.
The next big advantage is
about the animation editor.
In the new version,
when we use the animation editor,
if we record the animation,
every animation will have a fast key animation.
By using the fast key,
we can fix a lot of animation problems
and make some animation circles.
Now, after we have recorded the animation,
we can see that every key has a fast key.
If we move to a position without a fast key,
it will show the animation of the next layer.
If we drag the animation of the bottom layer
to the top layer,
we can see that the animation
is based on the top layer of the animation.
So everyone must pay attention
when you export the animation,
you must pay attention to the animation
that you need to export
and put it on the top layer,
not on the bottom layer.
Now, if we double click on the animation layer,
we can move the animation horizontally
to adjust the number of frames in the animation.
For example,
we can adjust the number of frames
after the animation of the costume
or the number of frames before.
If we right-click on the animation bar,
we can select the level of the animation layer.
This movement also has a positive and negative value.
If you select the positive value,
it will move backwards to the positive value.
If you select the negative value,
it will move to the negative value.
Now we can also select the cut animation layer,
which is to divide an animation layer into two.
Or we can select the merge animation layer.
Press the Shift key
and click on the animation layer,
you can choose more.
Then we can merge the animation layer together.
If we accidentally select
the animation layer that does not need to be merged,
we can press the Ctrl key
and click on it to cancel the selection.
These Aspects and Control commands
are commonly used in MyRisks 3.0.
The next one is to delete.
If we directly select an entire animation layer
and click on the delete button,
it will delete all the animations.
If we select only one animation layer,
and then right-click on the selected animation layer,
we can delete a single animation layer.
This is the animation layer.
Since we are talking about deleting,
let's talk about creating.
As the key point of the animation layer
will record the current location of the costume,
if we rotate the costume in the middle
and create a key point,
the key point in the middle will be blank.
There is no key point location,
and it will be changed in a linear fashion.
As you can see,
the blank space in the middle
I just rotated
has been changed in a linear fashion,
instead of being recorded
by our costume simulation.
If I choose to hide the animation,
we cannot see the previous animation layer,
we can only see the animation at the bottom.
However, it should be mentioned here that
if we delete the element back file,
even if you hide this animation layer,
it can still be deleted,
but we cannot see it.
However, it will still be deleted.
So if we don't want to delete it,
we have to delete this animation layer,
or drag the animation layer at the bottom
to the top layer,
because our animation is horizontal.
Since we are talking about hiding,
let's talk about the two buttons next to it.
One is to choose whether to display the key point.
If we hide this key point,
we cannot select the key point.
However, the animation of these key points
is still there.
The one next to it is to lock the animation,
to prevent us from editing
the animation to lock it.
Next, let's talk about
these lists on the right of the key point.
For example, if we want to copy the key point,
we need to copy the location of the animation
under this key point,
and then paste it to another key point.
This way, we can see that
the location of our costume
has already been copied.
We need to pay attention to the fact that
the key point cannot be copied
across layers.
So we need to copy the location of the animation.
If we want to select the key point at the bottom,
we need to click on the check button
to select the key point.
Then, we can select multiple key points.
We can then operate the key point
that we mentioned before.
It's the same as the single key point.
We can copy the key point,
paste the key point,
or delete the key point.
These are some of the advantages
of animation editors.
Let's take a look at some examples.
Let's see how these key points are used.
When we do animation,
sometimes, for example,
the model has a gap between the arm and the leg,
and it will take out the pants,
or there will be some problems with the hook.
Then we can delete
these key points that are recorded.
After deleting them,
we find that the arm is detached,
so we can copy the key point
to the leg,
and then we can redo the key point.
After deleting them,
the pants are back to their original position.
Then we can select the key point to create,
and record the location of the animation.
The problem of our fingers
hooking the pants
will be solved.
In the previous class,
we said that
during the simulation,
if the pants are taken out,
what should we do?
We can use the animation of the key point to fix it.
Then let's look at another example.
This is our G365,
this little elephant.
Its first point and last point
are the same animation,
but the material we simulated
is different.
It can't do the hand-tailed loop.
Because the animation of the last few points
basically didn't change much,
so we can delete the key point of the last few points,
and then copy the animation of the first point
and paste it to the last point.
This way,
our material can do the hand-tailed loop.
Now our animation of the first point,
because there is a transition point
with the key point in the middle,
so the material will slowly change
to the first point.
This way,
when we do the loop animation,
it will be very convenient
to solve the above problem.
Now we can take a look at this animation.
Its first point and last point,
the position of the material,
and the point information are the same.
So I will write down,
that the first point is the point and last point.
And it is same as before,
the position of the material
and the point of the here and there.
Again,
the process of the second point
is the same as before.
The next point is the point of the other points.
Because the first point is now eliminated,
the second point will be the point and last point.
It is the transition point.
Because the position of the left and right points
is seen from the left,
so the motion is the same.
So this is the right-hand side.
will also be preserved in the .exe format.
However, the key to clothing is that it will not be displayed.
Now let's talk about some other updates.
For example, the zipper.
Now our zipper heads and zippers can be separated
to edit their text and material.
In the new version, we can customize the zipper.
We can use the self-defined format to import our own BG zipper.
We can define it as a zipper head, zipper, or zipper head and zipper, or a zip.
When we choose a different option, it will have some different settings.
For example, we choose a zipper head, zipper, and import a model.
At this time, because we have two webpages,
one is a zipper head and the other is a zipper loop.
So when we define it, we need to define it in the file.
For example, we now choose a zipper head.
When we choose a web page, we can see the yellow highlight.
Is it a zipper or a zipper head?
We can select it and define it.
We have defined it before.
For example, if the mesh we just defined is a zipper head,
it can no longer be defined as a zipper loop.
It can be defined as a zipper loop.
There is a zipper position below.
This is actually when we choose a zipper,
it will have a locator.
The blue point we choose to set is the center of the locator.
Now it may look a little abstract.
But after a while, let's take a look and understand what it means.
I suggest that you try to set this blue point
in the position where the zipper and the zipper head intersect.
Now we choose this zipper,
we can see that this locator is the blue point we just set.
It is more convenient to rotate and move the zipper.
The last update we have is that
we can now apply Substance's SBA-CVR material
to the button or the model or the component.
In the past, we could only apply it to the fabric.
Now, these accessories can use Substance's material.
That's all for the introduction of the new features of MLS Designer 12.
If you have any questions,
you can ask me now.
You can also ask me questions about MLS Designer you usually use.
I'll be happy to answer them.
Thank you.
Thank you, MLS Designer.
Do you have any questions?
If you have any questions,
you can ask us right away.
We can ask you questions easily in the afternoon.
Yes, yes.
Is there no question left?
Oh, there is a question.
I'm looking for your questions.
I just want to ask, if the key point is moving, will the center of the key point move?
The center of the key point won't move.
It will move in some places.
Yes, it will move in some places.
I want to ask about the key point.
You mentioned that if the center of the key point is moving, will the center of the key point move?
The center of the key point doesn't need to move.
It depends on the scope of the problem.
Sometimes, the center of the key point moves to the middle of the key point.
Sometimes, it moves to the middle of the key point.
Sometimes, it moves to the back of the key point.
If the solution is in line with the physical law,
the center of the key point doesn't need to be moved.
We can keep the center of the key point without any problem.
Because the basic principle of animation recording is that
each point will be simulated separately,
and then keep the zero point information,
and then move to the next point.
So, as long as the animation is normal, it doesn't need to be removed.
You just need to remove the one with a problem,
and then record the center of the key point separately.
That's it.
Thank you.
There is another question.
You mentioned that the BNT modeling line can be symmetrical.
If my board is an asymmetrical shape,
can't it be symmetrical?
Right?
No.
If only the upper part is asymmetrical,
but the lower part is symmetrical,
it is still possible.
If your BNT is a line of symmetrical boards,
it is symmetrical.
For example,
if the upper part of your clothes is not symmetrical,
but the lower part of your skirt is symmetrical,
for example,
the control D,
or the symmetry edition board,
if we have the settings,
it will be symmetrical.
So, it can be symmetrical.
Yes.
Thank you.
Any other questions?
Yes.
You can ask the questions you usually use.
If there is no problem with the setting,
I will check the chat box.
Let me see if the online friends have any questions.
If you have any questions,
you can ask me later during the break.
You can also ask me if you have any questions.
I checked and there is no comment on our B站.
Why?
Oh, I see that you have considered joining the TOOP network, right?
Yes, we have. We are working on it.
The file house has been newly built.
But it is a bit difficult to develop it.
So we may have to wait a little longer.
But the optimization of the TOOP network is the most important part of our project this year.
The connection between the TOOP network and the board is not open.
But is the number of points in each board area the same?
Yes, it needs to be aligned.
It is best to align at the border of the board.
Is the number of points between the two boards the same?
Yes.
Or at the border of the board.
At the border of the board.
Yes.
It needs to be aligned at the border of the board.
If it is not the same, the connection will be disconnected.
You can't use it according to the zero frequency and the zero point.
Because the connection between the board and the board is often broken.
Yes, there may be some problems with breaking.
OK.
So we try to ensure that the zero points at the border are aligned.
Let's change it to zero points at the border.
OK.
I checked it, and it seems that there are not many questions.
Okay.
Now we can move to the next part.